Her Car Wasn't Acting Right: Then, 'My Jaw Hit the Floor'
When nuts fall off a tree, they usually accumulate in piles at the tree's base — which is why Chris Persic found it odd that underneath the black walnut tree in the yard of his Pittsburgh home, there were very few walnuts.
CBS Pittsburgh News reports that mystery was solved this week after Persic got a call from his wife, Holly, who told him her car was making weird noises and that it smelled like something was burning.
"I told her to pop the hood, and this is the picture that she sent me!" he wrote Monday in a now-viral Facebook post.
Grass and some 200 walnuts had been piled up around the car's innards by squirrels.
"My jaw hit the floor," Persic told CBS News of receiving the text, adding: "They were everywhere, under the battery, near the radiator fan. The walnuts on the engine block were black and smelled like they were definitely roasting."
It took almost an hour to clean most of the walnuts out so they could get the car to the mechanic.
Once there, the mechanic found even more walnuts stashed where the Persics couldn't reach them.
Adding another layer to the story, at the time he got his wife's phone call, Persic was at a car dealership.
His own truck engine check light had come on as the truck started shaking oddly while accelerating.
Persic thinks a squirrel gnawed through or pulled out a fuel injector hose.
The walnuts had only started dropping a few weeks ago. "The squirrels worked pretty fast!" notes Persic, who says he's glad they've had rain lately.
If it had been any drier out, he fears the grass under the hood of his wife's car could've caught fire.
"Absolutely nuts... no pun intended," he wrote on Facebook.